[
    {
        "question": "Thimphu is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Bhutan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the `Ocean State`?",
        "answer": "Rhode Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to Clemson University?",
        "answer": "South Carolina"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the state of Mississippi?",
        "answer": "Jackson"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cities of Xai-Xai, Panda, and Beira are in what country?",
        "answer": "Mozambique"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who named the Pacific Ocean?",
        "answer": "Ferdinand Magellan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you find `Aphrodite`s Rock`?",
        "answer": "Cyprus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the smallest borough of New York City by land area?",
        "answer": "Manhattan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prague is the capital of which European country?",
        "answer": "Czech Republic"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is associated with Alcatraz?",
        "answer": "San Francisco"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only country that displays the Bible on its national flag?",
        "answer": "The Dominican Republic"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which US state is Yale University located?",
        "answer": "Connecticut"
    },
    {
        "question": "What two US state capitals are named for people who were executed?",
        "answer": "Raleigh and St. Paul"
    },
    {
        "question": "What historic plaza is named for the first publisher of the `Dallas Morning News`?",
        "answer": "Dealey Plaza"
    },
    {
        "question": "What capital city is built around the famous Plaza Mayor and Puerta del Sol?",
        "answer": "Madrid"
    },
    {
        "question": "The seismic belt called the Ring of Fire surrounds what body of water?",
        "answer": "The Pacific Ocean"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country was policed by the Blackshirts for almost 25 years?",
        "answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Budapest is the capital of which European country?",
        "answer": "Hungary"
    },
    {
        "question": "What colours are on the Belgian flag?",
        "answer": "Yellow, black and red"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Suriname?",
        "answer": "Paramaribo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Venice`s Contarini Fasan Palace is traditionally believed to be the home of which Shakespearean heroine?",
        "answer": "The Palace is traditionally believed to be the home of Desdemona, Othello`s doomed wife in the Shakespeare play `Othello`."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Band-Aid supergroup was formed in 1984 to raise money for famine relief in what troubled African nation?",
        "answer": "Ethiopia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Bhutan`s national sport?",
        "answer": "Archery -- It was born out of necessity as bows and arrows were used to repel Tibetans and British invaders in the 19th century."
    },
    {
        "question": "In which Alaskan town do almost all residents live in the same building?",
        "answer": "In the small town of Whittier, Alaska, almost all residents live in the same building \u2014 a property called Begich Towers"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US States end with the letter N?",
        "answer": "Michigan, Washington, Oregon and Wisconsin"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the state motto for California?",
        "answer": "Eureka"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the only U.S. state whose motto is in French?",
        "answer": "Minnesota`s motto is  `L`etoile du Nord,` which in English is `Star of the North.`"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. state has the motto `Equal Rights`?",
        "answer": "Wyoming"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the `Sunshine State`?",
        "answer": "Florida"
    },
    {
        "question": "The US has shoreline along which oceans?",
        "answer": "Atlantic, Arctic and Pacific"
    },
    {
        "question": "The port city of Sheboygan is located in which US state?",
        "answer": "Wisconsin"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which island boasts of being Napoleon`s birthplace?",
        "answer": "Corsica"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which continent is home to the Tasmanian Devil?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the lowest land point on Earth?",
        "answer": "Dead Sea shore, Israel"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state capital is both the oldest and the highest in the country?",
        "answer": "Santa Fe"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mount Godwin Austen, located in the Karakoram mountain range, is better known as what?",
        "answer": "K2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. state has the unofficial motto `May The 14th Star Shine Bright`?",
        "answer": "Vermont (The unofficial motto \u201cStella Quarta Decima Fulgeat\u201d was adopted in 2015 after being proposed by a Vermonter Latin student.)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pennsylvania has what patriotic motto?",
        "answer": "`Virtue, Liberty and Independence`"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the lowest freshwater lake by altitude in the world?",
        "answer": "Israel"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the first country to declare internet a legal right?",
        "answer": "Finland"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which U.S. state are the Great Sand Dunes located?",
        "answer": "Colorado"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which U.S. state was Taylor Swift born?",
        "answer": "Pennsylvania"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Canadian island is famously known for its mussels?",
        "answer": "Prince Edward Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state hosts the world lumberjack championship?",
        "answer": "Wisconsin"
    },
    {
        "question": "Swiftcurrent Mountain is in what United States National Park?",
        "answer": "Glacier National Park"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest river delta in the world?",
        "answer": "The Ganges-Brahmaputra Delta"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the southernmost country in the European Union with no Mediterranean coastline?",
        "answer": "Portugal"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of Sri Lanka`s official languages also has official status in Singapore and parts of\u202fIndia?",
        "answer": "Tamil"
    },
    {
        "question": "The unofficial Wei\u00dfwurst\u00e4quator, or `white sausage equator`, separates Bavaria and the south from the rest of which country?",
        "answer": "Germany"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the Southern Tropic also called?",
        "answer": "Tropic of Capricorn"
    }
]